Guide to the Standard Bible Committee Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Standard Bible Committee Records
1939-1973
RG 70
Yale University Divinity School Library
4.5
(12 boxes)
The collection includes agendas, notes and working drafts that document the Committee's progress in its translation revision work. There is a small amount of material related to Committee procedures and publicity material. There is interesting documentation of public reaction to the new Revised Standard Version. The Standard Bible Committee was organized in 1929 by the International Council of Religious Education. The Committee was authorized in 1937 to proceed with the revision of the English translation of the Bible. The Committee's work resulted in the Revised Standard Version of the Bible. The Revised Standard Version of the New Testament was published in 1946, the entire Bible in 1952, and the Apocrypha in 1957. The work of the Committee was ongoing, to provide for future translation revisions.
Standard Bible Committee
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Shortly after the appearance of the American Standard Version of the Bible in 1901, newly discovered papyri gave Biblical scholars revolutionary insight into the language of the New Testament period. These texts provided a key to the exact meaning of obscure words, and contained many examples of the grammatical usage of the time. In response to this new knowledge, the Standard Bible Committee was organized in 1929 by the International Council of Religious Education. The Committee was authorized in 1937 to proceed with the revision of the English translation of the Bible.
The Revised Standard Version of the New Testament was published in 1946, the entire Bible in 1952, and the Apocrypha in 1957. The work of the Standard Bible Committee was necessarily ongoing, in order to keep future editions of the RSV on the forefront of new scholarship. In 1969 six Catholic scholars joined the Committee to assist in the preparation of an RSV edition which would be acceptable to both Protestants and Catholics. In 1972 an Orthodox Biblical scholar was also invited to join the Committee, as a step toward the preparation of a Bible produced and accepted by these three Christian traditions.
Members of the Old and New Testament sections of the Standard Bible Committee prior to 1952 included:
Luther A. Weigle, Yale University, - Old Testament and New Testament, Chairman
Julius A. Bewer, Union Theological Seminary - Old Testament
Henry J. Cadbury, Harvard University - New Testament
Edgar J. Goodspeed, University of Chicago - New Testament
James Moffatt, Union Theological Seminary - Old Testament and New Testament, Executive Secretary
William R. Taylor, University of Toronto - Old Testament
Walter Russell Bowie, Unioin Theological Seminary - New Testament
George Dahl, Yale University - Old Testament
Frederick C. Grant, Union Theological Seminary - New Testament
Willard L. Sperry, Harvard University - Old Testament
Leroy Waterman, University of Michigan - Old Testament
Millar Burrows, Yale University - Old Testament and New Testament
Clarence T. Craig, Oberlin Graduate School of Theology - New Testament
Abdel R. Wentz, Lutheran Theological Seminary, Gettysburg - New Testament
Kyle M. Yates, Southern Baptist Theological Seminary - Old Testament
William F. Albright, Johns Hopkins University - Old Testament
J. Philip Hyatt, Vanderbilt University - Old Testament
Herbert G. May, Oberlin Graduate School of Theology - Old Testament
Harry M. Orlinsky, Jewish Institute of Religion - Old Testament
Fleming James, University of the South - executive Secretary of the Old Testament Section
Scope and Contents
I Old Testament
II Apocrypha
III New Testament
IV Records of Committee Work
V Presentation and Evaluation
Agendas, notes, and/or working drafts illustrating the progress of the Committee's work are available for all of the Old Testament except Ezekiel, Daniel, and the Minor Prophets, for most Apocryphal books, and for the entire New Testament. These documents are generally in a mimeographed format with holograph annotations. Documentation is more complete for the Old Testament and Apocrypha than for the New Testament.
The working papers of the Standard Bible Committee found in Series I, II, and III form the substantive core of this collection. Committee members known to be involved in the production of particular documents are noted. Series IV provides a small amount of additional information about Committee procedures. Series V, Presentation and Evaluation, includes publicity material and interesting documentation of public reaction to the new Revised Standard Version.
Personal papers of two Committee members are available in the Yale libraries. Papers of Luther A. Weigle, chairman of the Standard Bible Committee for thirty-six years, are located at Sterling Memorial Library. Papers of Millar Burrows, member of both the Old and New Testament sections, are available in YDSL Record Group No. 30.
Arrangement
I. Old Testament
II. Apocrypha
III. New Testament
IV. Records of Committee Work
V. Presentation and Evaluation
Bible -- Translating; Bible -- Versions; Biblical scholars; Burrows, Millar, 1889-1980; Cadbury, Henry J. (Henry Joel), 1883-1974; Goodspeed, Edgar J. (Edgar Johnson), 1871-1962; Moffatt, James, 1870-1944; Weigle, Luther A. (Luther Allan), 1880-1976; Standard Bible Committee
- Old Testament, 1939-1951; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into two sections:
  A. Agendas, notes, working drafts
  B. Galley proofs
  The material is arranged in canonical order within each section. One folder of miscellaneous material follows each canonical sequence.
  - Agendas, Notes, Working Drafts
    - Genesis: Agenda and notes (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Genesis: Working draft # 4 - Ch. 3:7a-Ch. 24 (Revised by Moffatt), 1939 Oct (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Genesis: Working draft #4 - Ch. 25-50 (Revised by Moffatt), 1939 Oct (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Exodus: Notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Exodus: Working draft - Ch. 1-21 (Moffatt edited), 1940 Mar (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Exodus: Working draft- Ch. 22-40 (Moffatt edited), 1940 Mar (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Leviticus: Notes (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Leviticus: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1939 Dec
    - Numbers: Notes (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Numbers: Working draft - Ch. 1-16: 50a (Moffatt edited), 1939 Dec (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Numbers: Working draft - Ch. 16: 50b-Ch. 36 (Moffatt edited), 1939 Dec (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Deuteronomy: Agenda and notes (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Deuteronomy: Working draft - Ch. 1-15:20 (Moffatt edited), 1941 Feb (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Deuteronomy: Working draft - Ch. 15:21-Ch. 34 (Moffatt edited), 1941 Feb (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Joshua: Agenda and notes (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Joshua: Working draft # 2 (Committee revised, Moffatt edited), 1939 Dec (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Judges: Agenda and notes (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Judges: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Sep (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Ruth: Agenda and notes (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Ruth: Working draft #2 (Moffatt; 2 cop., one annotated by Driver?), 1939 Jun (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1 Samuel: Agenda and notes (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1 Samuel: Working draft - Ch. 1-11 (Moffatt edited), 1940 Jun (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1 Samuel: Working draft - Ch. 21-31 (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jan, Jun (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 2 Samuel: Agenda and notes (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 2 Samuel: Working draft - Ch. 1-21 (Moffatt edited), 1942 Mar (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 2 Samuel: Working draft- Ch. 22-23:7 (Taylor's report on poetical portions), 1942 Jan (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - 2 Samuel: Working draft - Ch. 23: g-Ch. 24 (Moffatt edited), 1942 Mar (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - 1 Kings: Agenda and notes
    - 1 Kings: Working draft - Ch. 1-5: 18a (Moffatt edited), 1942 Mar (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1 Kings: Working draft - Ch. 5:18b-Ch. 7 (Moffatt edited, revised 1943) (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - 1 Kings: Working draft - Ch. 8-22 (Moffatt edited), 1942 Mar (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 2 Kings: Agenda and notes (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 2 Kings: Working draft - Ch. 1-13 (Revised), 1942 June (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 2 Kings: Working draft - Ch. 13-25 (Revised), 1942 June (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 1 Chronicles: Agenda and notes (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - 1 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 1-9 (Waterman; Revised 1949) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 1 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 10-22 (Revised), 1948 Aug (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - 1 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 23-27(Revised), 1950 Feb (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 1 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 28,29 (Revised), 1948 Aug (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 2 Chronicles: Agenda and notes (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 2 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 1-5 (Revised), 1949 Aug (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - 2 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 6 (Revised), 1950 Feb (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - 2 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 7,8 (Revised), 1949 Aug (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - 2 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 9,10 (Revised), 1950 Feb (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - 2 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 11-17,19-22 (Revised), 1949 Aug (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - 2 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. l8, 23, 25, 26 (Revised), 1950 Feb (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - 2 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 27-30 (Some by Irwin; revised August and November, 1949,and November 1950), 1949 Aug-1950 Nov (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - 2 Chronicles: Working draft - Ch. 31-36 (James; revised 1949, November) (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Ezra: Agenda and notes (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Ezra: Working draft (Revised), 1944 Mar (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Nehemiah: Agenda and notes (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Nehemiah: Working draft (Revised), 1948 Aug-Nov,1950 Mar (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Esther: Agenda and notes (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Esther: Working drafts, 2 cop. with different annotations (Revised), 1942 Jun (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Job: Agenda (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Job: Notes (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Job: Working draft - Ch. 1-12: 23a (Irwin), 1945 Jun 1946 Aug (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Job: Working draft - Ch. 12:23b-Ch. 42 (Revised), 1948 Feb, Jun (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Psalms: Agenda - Burrows, Cadbury, Grant (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Psalms: Agenda - May, James, Sperry, Taylor (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Psalms: Agenda - Weigle (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Psalms: Notes (Box 3, Folder 62,63)
    - Psalms: Working draft - 1-21 (Taylor;Committee revised; Moffatt edited), 1940 Jan (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Psalms: Working draft - 22-36 (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jun (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Psalms: Working draft - 37-50 (Revised), 1942,1943 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Psalms: Working draft - 51-65 (Revised), 1944 May (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Psalms: Working draft - 66-Bl (Taylor), 1945 Jun (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Psalms: Working draft - 90-119 (Revised), 1942,1943 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Psalms: Working draft - 120-150 (Moffatt edited), 1941Jun, Jul; 1942 Jan (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Proverbs: Agenda (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Proverbs: Notes (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Proverbs: Working draft - Ch. 1-9 (Burrows), 1945 Jun (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Proverbs: Working draft - Ch. 10-19:19 (mostly Burrows), 1947 Sep (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Proverbs: Working draft - Ch. 15-31 (Revised), 1947 Dec (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Ecclesiastes: Agenda (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Ecclesiastes: Corr. re. Eccl. 12:1-S, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Ecclesiastes: Notes (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Ecclesiastes: Working draft (Revised), 1943 Jun, Dec;1945 Dec (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Song of Solomon: Agenda and notes (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Song of Solomon: Working draft (Revised), 1946 Aug (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Isaiah: Agenda - Bowie, Flack, Scott (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Isaiah: Agenda - Dahl, Coffin, Swim (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Isaiah: Agenda - Irwin, James, Muilenburg, Orlinsky, Turner (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Isaiah: Agenda - Weigle (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Isaiah: Notes (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Isaiah: Working draft - Ch. 1-12 (Revised), 1948 Aug (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Isaiah: Working draft - Ch. 13-20 (Revised), 1948 Dec (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Isaiah: Working draft - Ch. 21-27 (Revised), 1949 Jun (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Isaiah: Working draft - Ch. 28-33 (Revised), 1948 Dec (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Isaiah: Working draft - Ch. 34-39 (Dahl), 1946 Aug (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Isaiah: Working draft - Ch. 40-49 (Revised), 1949 Mar, Apr (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Isaiah: Working draft - Ch. 50-66, 1949 Jun (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Jeremiah: Agenda and notes (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Jeremiah: Working draft - Ch. 1-4 (Revised), 1945 Dec (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Jeremiah: Working draft - Ch. 5,6 (Revised), 1948 Jun (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Ch. 7 (Revised), 1945 Dec (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Ch. 8 (Revised), 1948 Aug (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Ch. 9,10 (Revised), 1949 Jun (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Ch. 11 (Revised), 1946 Dec (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Jeremiah: Working draft - Ch. 12,13 (Revised), 1949 Jun (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Ch. 14-17 (Revised), 1949 Aug (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - 18-20 (Revised), 1946 Dec (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Jeremiah: Working draft - Ch. 21-23 (Revised), 1947 Jun (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Ch. 24-30 (Revised), 1946 Dec (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Ch. 31 (Revised), 1948 Aug (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Jeremiah: Working draft - Ch. 32-34:16 (Revised), 1947 Mar (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Ch. 34:17-35 (Revised), 1947 Jun (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Ch. 36 (Revised), 1946 Dec (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Ch. 37-41 (Revised), 1947 Jun (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Jeremiah: Working draft - Ch. 42-44 (Revised), 1949 Aug (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Ch. 45,46 (Revised), 1948 Jun (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Ch. 47-49 (Revised), 1949 Aug (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Jeremiah: Working draft - Ch. 50, 1948 Jun (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Ch. 51 (Revised), 1949 Aug (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Ch. 52 (Revised), 1950 Feb (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Lamentatlons: Agenda and notes (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Lamentations: Working draft (Taylor), 1946 Aug (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - General and misc. notes (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Galley Proofs
    - Genesis 1:1-4:23, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Genesis (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Exodus (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Leviticus (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Deuteronomy (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Joshua (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Judges (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Ruth (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - 1 Samuel (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - 2 Samuel (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - 1 Kings (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - 2 Kings (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - 1 Chronicles (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - 2 Chronicles (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Ezra (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Nehemiah (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Esther (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Job (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Psalms 1-49 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Psalms 50-106 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Psalms 107-150 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - Proverbs (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - Ecclesiastes (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Song of Solomon (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Isaiah 1:1-38:S (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Isaiah 38:9-ch. 66 (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Jeremiah 1:1-28:16 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Jeremiah 28:17-ch. 52 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Lamentations (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Ezekiel (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - Daniel (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Hosea (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Joel, Amos, Obadiah, Jonah (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Micah, Nabum, Habakkuk, Zephaniah (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Haggai, Zechariah, Malachi (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Notes to galley proofs: Daniel - Zechariah (some books omitted) (Box 7, Folder 140)
- Apocrypha, 1953-1955; Series II
  The agendas, notes and drafts of this series are arranged alphabetically by book. One folder of miscellaneous material follows the alphabetical sequence.
  - Additions to the Book of Esther: Agenda (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Additions to the Book of Esther: Working draft (Revised by Committee), 1955 Jun (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Baruch: Agenda (Box 8, Folder 142)
  - Baruch: Working draft (Revised by Committee), 1955 Jun (Box 8, Folder 142)
  - Bel and the Dragon: Agenda (Box 8, Folder 143)
  - Bel and the Dragon: Working draft (Revised by Committee), 1953 (Box 8, Folder 143)
  - Ecclesiasticus: Agenda (Box 8, Folder 144)
  - Ecclesiasticus: Notes (Box 8, Folder 145)
  - Ecclesiasticus: First draft (Weigle): (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - Ecclesiasticus: Prologue, Ch. 1-22 (Revised by Committee), 1953 (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - Ecclesiasticus: First draft (Pfeiffer):Ch. 13-27, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 147)
  - Ecclesiasticus: First draft (Cadbury): Ch. 28-31, 1954 Mar (Box 8, Folder 148)
  - Ecclesiasticus: First draft (Weigle): Ch. 32-37,39-40, 1954 Jan, Apr;n.d. (Box 8, Folder 149)
  - Ecclesiasticus: First draft (Grant): Ch. 38,41-43, 1954 Feb (Box 8, Folder 150)
  - Ecclesiasticus: First draft (Weigle): Ch. 44-51, 1954 Jan-Mar (Box 8, Folder 151)
  - Ecclesiasticus: Working draft- Prologue, Ch. 1-12 (Revised by Committee), 1953 Jun (Box 8, Folder 152)
  - Ecclesiasticus: Working draft - Ch. 13-35 (Revised by Committee), 1954 Jun (Box 8, Folder 153)
  - Ecclesiasticus: Working draft - Ch. 36-51 (Revised by Committee), 1954 Aug (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - 1 Esdras: Agenda and correspondence (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - 1 Esdras: First draft (Weigle), 1953 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - 1 Esdras: Working draft (Revised by Committee), 1953,1954 (Box 8, Folder 157)
  - 2 Esdras: Agenda (Box 8, Folder 158)
  - 2 Esdras: Notes and correspondence (Box 8, Folder 159)
  - 2 Esdras: Latin version - "Liber Ezrae Qvartvs" (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - 2 Esdras: Flrst draft (Metzger), 1953,1954 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - 2 Esdras: Working draft - Ch. 1,2 (Revised by Committee), 1953 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - 2 Esdras: Working draft - Ch. 3-16 (Revised by Committee), 1954 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Judith: Agenda (Box 9, Folder 164)
  - Judith: Working draft (Revised by Committee), 1953 Aug (Box 9, Folder 165)
  - 1 Maccabees: Agenda and notes (Box 9, Folder 166)
  - 1 Maccabees: First draft (Filson), 1953 (Box 9, Folder 167)
  - 1 Maccabees: Working draft- Ch.l-10 (Revised by Committee), 1953 Jun,Dec (Box 9, Folder 168)
  - Maccabees: Working draft - Ch. 11-16 (Revised by Committee), 1954 Aug (Box 9, Folder 169)
  - Maccabees: Agenda and notes (Box 9, Folder 170)
  - Maccabees: First draft (Cadbury): Ch. 1-4 (inc. 1 cop. ch. 3,4 handwritten), 1953 Jun, Jul (Box 9, Folder 171)
  - Maccabees: First draft (Weigle): Ch. 5-16, 1955 Apr. (Box 9, Folder 172)
  - Maccabees: Working draft Ch. 1,2 (Revised by Committee), 1953 Jun (Box 9, Folder 173)
  - Maccabees: Ch. 3-16 (Revised by Committee), 1955 Aug (Box 9, Folder 173)
  - The Prayer of Azariah and the Song of the Three Young Men (additions to Daniel): Agenda (Box 9, Folder 174)
  - The Prayer of Azariah and the Song of the Three Young Men: Working draft (Box 9, Folder 174)
  - The Prayer of Manasseh: Agenda (Box 9, Folder 175)
  - The Prayer of Manasseh: Working drafts (Revised by Committee), 1955 Jun (Box 9, Folder 175)
  - Susanna: Agenda, notes (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - Susanna: Working draft (Revised by Committee), 1953 Jan 30-31 (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - Tobit: Agenda (Box 9, Folder 177)
  - Tobit: Working draft (Revised by Committee), 1953 Jun, Dec (Box 9, Folder 178)
  - Wisdom: Agenda (Box 9, Folder 179)
  - Wisdom: Working draft (Revised by Committee), 1953 Jun,1955 Jun (Box 9, Folder 180)
  - General and misc. notes (Box 9, Folder 181)
- New Testament, 1939-1943-; Series III
  The working and final drafts in this series are arranged in canonical order. One folder of miscellaneous material follows the canonical sequence.
  - Matthew: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Apr (Box 10, Folder 182)
  - Matthew: Final draft, 1943 Jan (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - Mark: Working draft (Revised by Moffatt), 1939 Oct (Box 10, Folder 184)
  - Mark: Final draft, 1943 Feb (Box 10, Folder 185)
  - Luke: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Mar, Aug (Box 10, Folder 186)
  - Luke: Final draft (?) (1:1-2:7a missing), 1943? (Box 10, Folder 187)
  - John: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Apr (Box 10, Folder 188)
  - John: Final draft, 1942 Dec (Box 10, Folder 189)
  - Acts: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Aug (Box 10, Folder 190)
  - Acts: Final draft, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 191)
  - Romans: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jun (Box 10, Folder 192)
  - Romans: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 10, Folder 193)
  - 1 Corinthians: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Mar (Box 11, Folder 194)
  - 1 Corinthians: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 195)
  - 2 Corinthians: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Aug (Box 11, Folder 196)
  - 2 Corinthians: Revised, 1942 Dec (Box 11, Folder 197)
  - Galatians: Draft #2 - Sayner, July 1939;Revised, Moffatt, 1939 Oct (Box 11, Folder 198)
  - Galatians: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 198)
  - Ephesians: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Sep (Box 11, Folder 199)
  - Philippians: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Oct (Box 11, Folder 200)
  - Philippians: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 200)
  - Colossians: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Mar (Box 11, Folder 201)
  - Colossians: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 201)
  - 1 Thessalonians: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jul (Box 11, Folder 202)
  - 1 Thessalonians: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 202)
  - 2 Thessalonians: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jul (Box 11, Folder 203)
  - 2 Thessalonians: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 203)
  - 1Timothy: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Nov (Box 11, Folder 204)
  - 1 Timothy: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 204)
  - 2 Timothy: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Nov (Box 11, Folder 205)
  - 2 Timothy: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 205)
  - Titus: Working draft (Moffatt edited, October 1941; Revised by Committee, 11/28/41) (Box 11, Folder 206)
  - Titus: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 206)
  - Philemon: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Sep (Box 11, Folder 207)
  - Philemon: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 207)
  - Hebrews: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Dec (Box 11, Folder 208)
  - Hebrews: Revised, 1942 Nov (Box 11, Folder 209)
  - James: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Mar (Box 11, Folder 210)
  - James: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 210)
  - 1 Peter: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jul (Box 11, Folder 211)
  - 1 Peter: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 211)
  - 2 Peter: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jul (Box 11, Folder 212)
  - 2 Peter: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 212)
  - 1 John: Working draft (Moffatt edited) (Box 11, Folder 213)
  - 1 John: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 213)
  - 2 John: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jul (Box 11, Folder 214)
  - 2 John: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 214)
  - 3 John: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jul (Box 11, Folder 214)
  - 3 John: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 214)
  - Jude: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1941 Jul (Box 11, Folder 213)
  - Jude: Final draft, 1942 Jun (Box 11, Folder 213)
  - Revelation: Working draft (Moffatt edited), 1940 Mar (Box 11, Folder 215)
  - Revelation: Final draft, 1942 Dec (Box 11, Folder 216)
  - General and misc. notes (Box 11, Folder 217)
- Records of Committee Work, 1939-1968; Series IV
  The materials in this series are arranged by format.
  - List of books used by Bible Revision Committee, 1939-1951, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 218)
  - Photographs of Committee, of Luther Weigle, of dedication of Bible Room at Interchurch Center, 1965-1966, n.d.. (Box 12, Folder 219)
- Presentation and Evaluation, Series V
  The materials in this series are divided into the following categories:
  A. Magazine articles
  B. Newspaper clippings
  C. Pamphlets
  D. Miscellaneous manuscripts and correspondence
  E. Publicity material, news releases
  F. Commemorative material
  - Magazine articles
    - "The New Version" by Ralph Earle (Preacher's Magazine ), 1946 May-Jun (Box 12, Folder 220)